Register of the Adolf Hitler Miscellaneous Papers, 1878-1965
Hoover Institution Archives
Adolf Hitler Miscellaneous Papers,
1878-1965
XX237
Hitler, Adolf, 1889-1945
3 manuscript boxes, 2 oversize boxes, 2 card file boxes, 5 envelopes, 2 microfilm reels, 5 phonotape reels, 1 phonorecord (6.3 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Drafts (typewritten) of two speeches by Adolf Hitler, one relating to the shooting of Ernst Röhm and others, 1934, and the other delivered at a Nazi party convention, 1937; his appointment book, March to June, 1943; photographs, bust and a ceramic tile portrait of him; lists of books in his library; a copy of his death certificate; recordings of two speeches by him, 1937 and 1941; and miscellaneous office files of the German Imperial Chancellery, 1879-1945.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Access Points
Nationalsozialistische deutsche Arbeiter-Partei; National socialism; World War, 1939-1945; World War, 1939-1945--Germany; Germany; Germany--History--1933-1945; Statesmen--Germany; Phonotapes; Phonorecords; Germany. Reichskanzlei
Container List
- REICHSKANZLEI FILE, 1878-1944
  - Offical regulations and standing orders of the German government (Reichsregierung), 1924-1944 (Box 1., Folder 1)
  - Requests for monetary assistance, 1938-1943 (Folder 2)
  - Fund raising in Werder and the participation of the local fruit growers, 1936-1938 (Folder 3)
  - Air-raid shelter for the Reichskanzlei, 1944-1945. Includes floor plans of the Reichskanzlei (Folder 4)
  - Budget and financial affairs of the Reichskanzlei, 1878-1940 (Folder 5-6)
  - State funeral for Senior Embassy Official Gustav vom Rath, assassinated in Paris, 1938 (Folder 7)
  - Regulations on compulsory conservation (Eisernes Sparen), 1941-1945 (Folder 8)
  - Civil defense, emergency services, anti-aircraft defense, 1939-1944 (Folder 9)
  - Social insurance regulations, 1939-1943 (Folder 10)
  - Regulations for military pay, 1939-1944 (Folder 11)
  - Regulations for official travel, 1933-1944 (Box 2., Folder 1)
  - Verwaltungsakademien (Administrative academies) and DieVerwaltungs-Akademie, the handbook for the officials in the national socialist state, 1933-1936 (Folder 2)
  - The financial costs for building the Reichskanzlei shelter (presumably the air-raid shelter), 1944 (Folder 3)
  - Letters of admiration and requests to Adolf Hitler, primarily from women, 1935-1944 (Folder 4-6)
  - Miscellaneous, 1933-1944. Includes printed copy of Adolf Hitler's speech before the Reichstag, 1939 October 6 (Folder 7)
  - Luxenberg, Bruno, Report on grain cultivation, 1936 September-October (Folder 8)
  - Luxenberg, Bruno, The current situtation of the economy of nutrition, 1937 (Folder 9)
  - Awards signed by Adolf Hitler, n.d. (Box 3., Folder 1)
  - List of the new acquisitions for the library of the Reichskanzlei, 1939-1944 (Folder 2)
  - Form letters of the Private office of Adolf Hitler, ca. 1939 (Folder 3-4)
- SPEECHES AND WRITINGS, 1934-1937
  - Reichstag speech justifying the 30 June Röhm shootings, 1934 July 13. Typescript (Box 3., Folder 5)
  - "The Führer and Reichskanzler Adolf Hitler speaks," 1937 April 29. Typescript (see also microfilm) (Folder 6)
- SUBJECT FILE, 1944-1965
  - Adolf Hitler's death certificate, 1945 April 30 (copy) (Box 3., Folder 7)
  - 1944 July 20
    - Clippings, 1946-1965 (Folder 8)
    - United States Army reports, 1945. Includes report of the interrogation of Commander Franz Maria Liebig (see also microfilm) (Folder 9)
  - Library of Adolf Hitler. Bibliographic cards listing the book titles in Adolf Hitler's personal library (Box 4-5.)
- OVERSIZE MATERIAL.
  - Includes Adolf Hitler's appointment book, 1943 March-June; portrait of Adolf Hitler on ceramic tile, n.d.; and the household accounts for the Führer and Reichskanzler, 1942 (Box 6.)
- AUDIO-VISUAL MATERIAL, 1937-1945
  - See photograph card catalog (Box 10.A-V)
  - "Diacorso de Campo de Maggio," speech, 1937 September 28 (Box Tape cabinet, Tape Tape 1)
  - Anniversary of the founding of the National Socialist Workers' Party of Germany (NSDAP), speech, 1941 February 24 (Tape Tape 2-5)
  - The opening of the Winterhilfe campaign, speech, 1940 (Oversize Record cabinet)
  - "The Führer and Reichskanlzer Adolf Hitler Speaks," n.d. (Oversize Microfilm cabinet, Reel Reel 1)
  - Special interrogation report relating to 1944 July 20 (typescript in Box 3) (Reel Reel 2)